Donald Houldcroft Paper VHP2006/24
CCSU Veterans History Project
Donald Houldcroft Papers
Bulk, 1956-1976
1956 - 1976, 2006
VHP2006/24
CCSU Veterans History Project
75.0 Digital objects 1 interview DVD
This collection details experience of Donald Houldcroft as he served in U.S. Navy during the Vietnam War. The collection includes voide oral history interview, Photographs, and memorabilia.
Houldcroft, Donald, 1938 -
Custodial History note
All manuscripts and photographs donated were digitized and digitally preserved. The donor retained all original manuscripts and photographs.
Biographical/Historical note
Donald Houldcroft was born in 1938. He first enlisted in the U.S. Army but later joined the U.S. Navy in 1958. He served with U.S. Fleet Marine Force, a forces within the United States Department of the Navy that consists of both combative naval fleets and Marine Corps' forces, during Vietnam war. He was discharged in 1976. After the service, he received Master’s in Animal Science and spent his civilian life as a teacher.
Conditions Governing Access note
On-line access restricted. To view Donald Houldcroft's photos, interview, and memorabilia, please visit the CCSU Elihu Burritt Library in person.
United States. Army.; United States. Marine Corps. Fleet Marine Force.; United States. Navy.; Vietnam War, 1961-1975; Vietnam War, 1961-1975 -- Personal narrative, American; Vietnam War, 1961-1975--Medical care.; Đà Nã̆ng (Vietnam)
- Series I: Personal Papers, VHP2006/24.I
  - Asia Hotel (Taipei, Taiwan) luggage tag., n.d.; VHP2006/24.I.1
  - Quang-Nam Badge, n.d.; VHP2006/24.I.2
  - Force Logistic Command Patch, VHP2006/24.I.3
  - Donald Houldcroft's Bunk card, n.d.; VHP2006/24.I.4
  - Interview Synopsis, Nov. 9, 2006; VHP2006/24.I.5
- Series II: Multi-Media, VHP2006/24.II
  - Subseries A: Still Images, VHP2006/24.II
    - Class B of Hospital Corps School. Portsmouth, VA, 1962; VHP2006/24.II.1
      General note
      Donald Houldcroft (3rd row, 5th from left)
    - Ceremony at Newport Naval Station for Chief Petty Officers. Newport, RI, 1963; VHP2006/24.II.2
      Donald Houldcroft (back row, 3rd from left)
    - A party in Honolulu, HI, 1966 - 1968; VHP2006/24.II.3
    - Donald Houldcroft (2nd from right)at re-enlistment ceremony. Naval Supply Center. Pearl Harbor, HI, 1966 - 1968; VHP2006/24.II.4
    - Marine Training, before deployment to Vietnam. Camp Pendleton, CA, 1968; VHP2006/24.II.5
    - Marine Training, before deployment to Vietnam. Camp Pendleton, CA, 1968; VHP2006/24.II.6
    - Marine Training, before deployment to Vietnam. Camp Pendleton, CA, 1968; VHP2006/24.II.7
    - Training camp for field medical training school. Camp Pendleton, CA, 1969; VHP2006/24.II.8
    - Training camp for field medical training school. Camp Pendleton, CA, 1969; VHP2006/24.II.9
    - CH-47 Chinook helicopter lifting a marine during Marine Corps Training. Camp Pendleton, CA, 1969; VHP2006/24.II.10
    - Infiltration course. Camp Pendleton, CA, 1969; VHP2006/24.II.11
    - Infiltration course. Camp Pendleton, CA, 1969; VHP2006/24.II.12
    - Infiltration course. Camp Pendleton, CA, 1969; VHP2006/24.II.13
    - Donald Houldcroft in Da Nang, Vietnam, 1969; VHP2006/24.II.14
    - Vehicles on "Highway 1" (National road 1A). South Vietnam, 1969; VHP2006/24.II.15
    - Armored personnel carrier [M-706?] on "Highway 1" South Vietnam, 1969; VHP2006/24.II.16
    - Bridge on "Highway 1" Sotuh Vietnam, 1969; VHP2006/24.II.17
    - Marine base [?] Da Nang, Vietnam, 1969 - 1970; VHP2006/24.II.18
    - "Floor Show" in Da Nang, Vietnam, 1969 - 1970; VHP2006/24.II.19
    - Corpsman Donald Houldcroft at Headquarters Command Sergeant Office. Da Nang, Vietnam, 1969; VHP2006/24.II.20
    - Medical Jeep. Da Nang, Vietnam, 1969 - 1970; VHP2006/24.II.21
    - Marine Corps Headquarters. Da Nang, Vietnam, 1969 - 1970; VHP2006/24.II.22
    - Marine Corps member Bruce treating a Vietnamese child. Da Nang, Vietnam, 1969 - 1970; VHP2006/24.II.23
    - Bruce and Donald Houldcroft(Right)Da Nang, Vietnam, 1969 - 1970; VHP2006/24.II.24
    - Naval Support Activity Hospital. Da Nang, Vietnam, 1969 - 1970; VHP2006/24.II.25
    - Donald Houldcroft at Battalion Aid Station (Sick Bay) Da Nang, Vietnam, 1969 - 1970; VHP2006/24.II.26
    - Donald Houldcroft. Inside Battalion Aid Station - Sick Bay. Da Nang, Vietnam, 1969 - 1970; VHP2006/24.II.27
    - Donald Houldcroft at Battalion Aid Station. Da Nang, Vietnam, 1969 - 1970; VHP2006/24.II.28
    - Marine Driver working on log book. Vietnam, 1969 - 1970; VHP2006/24.II.29
    - Rice fields. Da Nang, Vietnam, 1969 - 1970; VHP2006/24.II.30
    - Shoreline. Da Nang, Vietnam, 1969 - 1970; VHP2006/24.II.31
    - Countryside. Da Nang, Vietnam, 1969 - 1970; VHP2006/24.II.32
    - Countryside. Da Nang, Vietnam, 1969 - 1970; VHP2006/24.II.33
    - French fort, Vietnam, 1969 - 1970; VHP2006/24.II.34
    - Farewell note written on photo of USS Charles P. Cecil (DD-835), April 1976; VHP2006/24.II.35
  - Subseries B: Moving Images, VHP2006/24.IIb
    - Oral history interview with Donald Houldcroft, Nov. 9, 2006; VHP2006/24.IIb.1; 1.0 dvd; Brown, Tanisha (Disk DVD VHP2006/24, Box VHP Interview 2006)